Tero Ankkuri teroank.dev

CONTACT

+358 40 7658 775 teroankkuri@gmail.com





ABOUT ME

Creative problem solver with a business background who decided to utilise their Excel enthusiasm properly and go for coding. Programmed the first time at 12 years old, always done IT and took courses at the Uni, but only this year decided to do it seriously and make a career out of it. Very capable of quickly adopting new concepts and all things IT. Take a glance at my portfolio site to see where I'm at!



EXPERIENCE

Analyst

UseLess Company 10/2020 - 5/2021

- Calculating carbon footprints for SM enterprises
- Proposing emission reduction pathways
- · General start-up business development

Trainee, Associate

PwC Finland 8/2019 - 2/2020

- Risk management -related data analyses and migration testings
- IT audits
- Development of CSR reporting

Finance Assistant

Arvato Financial Solutions 7/2017 - 9/2017

• Financing of clients' sales invoices

Customer Delight Specialist

Finnchat 1/2017 - 8/2017

• Supporting B2B and B2C customers on various websites through a chat service



EDUCATION

University of Jyväskylä

M.Sc. (Econ & B.A.) 2018 - 2021

- Major: Corporate Environmental Management
- Minor: Environmental studies

B.Sc. (Econ & B.A.) 2015 - 2018

- Major: Information System Science
- Minor: Accounting
- Bachelor's thesis on blockchain tehnology and different consensus mechanisms

Management Center Innsbruck

Student exchange in Innsbruck, Austria 2017 - 2018

• Studies in Business & Management module



LANGUAGE SKILLS

Finnish mother tongue

English excellent
Swedish sufficient
German basics



HOBBIES

- Crossfit
- Reading, broadening of mind and imagination
- Movies (dystopic movies especially)